<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Career - Category - Know Thyself</title>
        <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/categories/career/</link>
        <description>Career - Category - Know Thyself</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 21:57:40 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/categories/career/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>What is the procedure for getting a PhD in NIMHANS? Part 1</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are three ways to apply for a PhD admit
Path 1: The institute itself funds the three seats in the department (Only some departments have these fellowship seats). Commonly referred to as an institution fellowship. To get this, you must pass both an exam and an interview. The hardest entry is this one. MCQ questions from the field of specific department are frequently found on entrance exams.
Path 2: Having one&rsquo;s own external fellowship (UGC, CSIR, ICMR, etc.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What is the procedure for getting a PhD in NIMHANS? Part 2</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Visit the NIMHANS website to download the most recent entrance prospectus. To learn more about the eligibility requirements, course duration, costs, stipend, number of seats, etc., read the prospectus
The announcement is made during the first week of January, and is then followed by an entrance exam, an interview, a selection announcement, admission, and the start of the course by July first week
Almost every faculty has a project that is funded by the government or the institution.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What is the procedure for getting a PhD in NIMHANS? Part 3</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-3/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/procedure-for-phd-3/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[During the first week of January every year, keep an eye on the NIMHANS website
During the first week of January, the notification and online application are distributed The number of courses that one may apply for is subject to specific limitations Review the prospectus to learn about new courses, eligibility requirements, paperwork needed, etc Make an effort to contact current students to gain their input on the format of the courses and exams Prepare for the exam, which will be held in the final week of March.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to prepare for a masters or PhD in Neuroscience</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-do-i-prepare-for-exam/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-do-i-prepare-for-exam/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Exam coverage is sufficient for a non-bio/medical person to pass with proper reading and effort
Get Instant notes in Neurosciences. Read from page first to last. If you get lost and miserable, don&rsquo;t worry. Estimated completion time is 14 days Reread the Neuroscience/Physiology-focused section of the CBSE biology textbook. Estimated completion time is seven days Dale Purves&rsquo; book Neuroscience is easy to read quickly to get the gist of the subject.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How is the course? Part 1 | MPhil</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-is-the-course-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-is-the-course-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[MPhil Neurophysiology and MPhil Neuroscience were two distinct courses with two distinct objectives. My MPhil was in Neurosciences, and I&rsquo;m currently completing on my PhD in Neurophysiology
Almost every academic and scientific event taking place on campus is open to students. Many students don&rsquo;t look into these possibilities. Some of them include mortality seminars, brain-cutting sessions, seminars, workshops, colloquia, journal and seminar clubs. Make sure that these activities don&rsquo;t conflict with the course&rsquo;s schedules.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How is the course? Part 2 | PhD</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-is-the-course-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/how-is-the-course-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The first month after students enroll in the course is a habituation month. Coursework and training in animal handling and research start in the second month and last for about three months
Doctoral students are placed in various labs during this time. They go to one seminar and one journal club meeting each week. Students are free to participate in additional teaching sessions held for MPhils. Each professor used to teach two or three sessions in their area of expertise.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mentees</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/interns/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/interns/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Below are the brave souls currently or previously undergoing Wax On, Wax Off with me. All of them not only mastered the science but also survived my Jack of all, Master of None approach to supervision, which involved a heavy dose of discussions and the occasional hour long tangential journey through science, life and stories.
[Name | Where did they come from | Where are they now | What are you up-to]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mentor Mentee</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/hiring/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/hiring/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Thank you for reaching out to me to know more about opportunities for working together. Here is everything you need to know.
As a freshly minted scientist and a long term resident at Centre for Consciousness Studies, NIMHANS my five year goal (2026-2030) is to establish a new research area Sense of Self at the same time teach and train existing and new members and contribute meaningfully to all the great projects happening at the centre.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sense of Self</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/sense-of-self/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/sense-of-self/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ownserhsip, Embodiment, Agency, Peripersonal space]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What is a career option?</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/career-quirks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Rahul</author>
    <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/blog/career/career-quirks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The opinions of these so-called motivational gurus, passion seekers, and career counsellors on how to define one&rsquo;s career are about as useful as conversations over what colour parachutes are worth. The modern job market is so vast that it would be impossible to locate an ideal career path in a single lifetime. In order to raise best sellers, creators fabricate the bogeyman of the &ldquo;passion driven world.&rdquo;
Passion is not a long-lost artefact that can be revived with enough blood and sweat.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
