<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on Know Thyself</title>
    <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on Know Thyself</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 21:57:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for a masters or PhD in Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/how-do-i-prepare-for-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</author>
      <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/how-do-i-prepare-for-exam/</guid>
      <description>Exam coverage is sufficient for a non-bio/medical person to pass with proper reading and effort
Get Instant notes in Neurosciences. Read from page first to last. If you get lost and miserable, don&amp;rsquo;t worry. Estimated completion time is 14 days Reread the Neuroscience/Physiology-focused section of the CBSE biology textbook. Estimated completion time is seven days Dale Purves&amp;rsquo; book Neuroscience is easy to read quickly to get the gist of the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is the course? Part 1 | MPhil</title>
      <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/how-is-the-course-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</author>
      <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/how-is-the-course-1/</guid>
      <description>MPhil Neurophysiology and MPhil Neuroscience were two distinct courses with two distinct objectives. My MPhil was in Neurosciences, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently completing on my PhD in Neurophysiology
Almost every academic and scientific event taking place on campus is open to students. Many students don&amp;rsquo;t look into these possibilities. Some of them include mortality seminars, brain-cutting sessions, seminars, workshops, colloquia, journal and seminar clubs. Make sure that these activities don&amp;rsquo;t conflict with the course&amp;rsquo;s schedules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a career option?</title>
      <link>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/career-quirks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 21:57:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>rhlvenugopal@gmail.com (xxxx)</author>
      <guid>https://rahulvenugopal.github.io/haveyoumetrahul/research/career-quirks/</guid>
      <description>The opinions of these so-called motivational gurus, passion seekers, and career counsellors on how to define one&amp;rsquo;s career are about as useful as conversations over what colour parachutes are worth. The modern job market is so vast that it would be impossible to locate an ideal career path in a single lifetime. In order to raise best sellers, creators fabricate the bogeyman of the &amp;ldquo;passion driven world.&amp;rdquo;
Passion is not a long-lost artefact that can be revived with enough blood and sweat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
